Inventory of the California Department of Industrial Relations. Division of Statistics and Research Records, 1913 - 1984
Labor Archives and Research Center
- UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE, 1922-1935 (Pamphlets listed by publication date) (Box Box 27)
  - U. S. Bureau of Labor Statistics. Operation of Unemployment Benefit Plans and Insurance Systems, 1931 and 1932, Bulletin No. 544, 1933
  - "Partial Stabilization of Workers' Incomes Through Unemployment Insurance," The Annals, March 1931
  - Past and Present of Unemployment Insurnace, by Sir William H. Beveridge, 1930
  - Public Unemployment Insurnace, National Association of Manufacturers and National Industrial Council, 1930
  - Some Comments on Unemployment Insurance, by P. Tecumseh Sherman of the New York Bar, 1931
  - U. S. Department of Commerce, State Legislation for Unemployment Relief: From January 1, 1932, to May 31, 1932.
  - U. S. Bureau of Labor Statistics. Unemployment-Benefit Plans in the United States and Unemployment Insurance in Foreign Countries, 1931
  - Unemployment Insurance, by Reinhard A. Hohaus, 1930
  - Unemployment Insurance, by Dr. William M. Leiserson, Chairman, Ohio Commission on Unemployment Insurance, 1932
  - Unemployment Insurance, Chamber of Commerce of the United States, 1931
  - Unemployment Insurance..., by Mary B. Gilson, 1933
  - U. S. Congress. Senate...Hearings, Unemployment Insurance, 1932
  - U. S. Bureau of Labor Statistics. Unemployment Insurance and Reserves in the United States, compiled by Laura A. Thompson, 1935
  - U. S. Congress. House...Hearings, Unemployment Insurance for Seamen, 1941
  - National Industrial Conference Board, Unemployment Insurance in Theory and Practice, Research Report Number 51, 1922
- UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE--UNEMPLOYMENT RESERVE PROGRAMS 1930-1933 (Pamphlets listed alphabetically by title) (Box Box 28)
  - American Plan for Unemployment Reserve Funds, An..., American Association for Labor Legislation, 1930
  - Company Loans to Unemployed Workers, Princeton University, Industrial Relations Section, 1931
  - Compulsory Unemployment Reserve Funds, American Association for Labor Legislation, 1931
  - Economic Security for Employees, Industrial Reserves Corp. of America, 1933
  - Essentials of a Program of Unemployment Reserves, National Industrial Conference Board, Inc., 1933
  - "Making Booms Bear the Burden of Relief--Some Financial Implications of Unemployment Reserves," by Sumner H. Slichter, Harvard Business Review, April 1933
  - Progress Toward Unemployment Reserves, by John B, Andrews, Secretary, American Association for Labor Legislation, 1932
  - "Progressive Employers Favor Unemployment Reserve Funds," by Ernest G. Draper and Henry S. Dennison, American Labor Legislation Review, V. XXI, No. 1, reprinted by American Association of Labor Legislation
  - Rochester Unemployment Benefit Plan, Rochester Chamber of Commerce, Industrial Management Council, 1931
  - Unemployment Reserve Funds: An American Plan to Stabilize Jobs and Purchasing Power, by John B. Andrews, Secretary, American Association for Labor Legislation, 1930
- UNION DEMOCRACY, 1953-1960 (Pamphlets listed alphabetically by title) (Box Box 28)
  - AFL-CIO Codes of Ethical Practices, 1953
  - Union Democracy, New York State Department of Labor, 1960
  - Unions and Union Leaders of Their Own Choosing, Fund of the Republic, 1957
- WOMEN WORKERS 1922-1930. U.S. DEPT. OF LABOR, WOMEN'S BUREAU (Pamphlets listed by date of publication) (Box Box 29)
  - Women Street Car Conductors and Ticket Agents, Bulletin No. 11, 1921
  - Industrial Opportunities and Training for Women and Girls, Bulletin No. 13, 1922
  - Proceedings of the Women's Industrial Conference, Bulletin No. 33, 1923
  - Domestic Workers and their Employment Relations, Bulletin No. 39, by Mary V. Robinson, 1924
  - Married Women in Industry, Bulletin No. 38, by Mary N. Winslow, 1924
  - Facts About Working Women, Bulletin No. 46, 1925
  - Family Status of Breadwinning Women in Four Selected Cities, Bulletin No. 41, 1925
  - Lost Time and Labor Turnover in Cotton Mills, Bulletin No. 52, 1926
  - Status of Women in the Government Service in 1925, Bulletin No. 53, by Bertha M. Nienberg, 1926
  - Changing Jobs, Bulletin No. 54, 1926
  - Women in the Fruit-Growing and Canning Industries in the State of Washington, Bulletin No. 47, 1926
  - Eighth Annual Report of the Director of the Women's Bureau, Fiscal Year Ended June 30, 1926
  - Effects of Applied Research Upon the Employment Opportunities of American Women, Bulletin No. 50, 1926
  - Short Talks About Working Women, Bulletin No. 59, 1927
  - Tenth Annual Report of the Director of the Women's Bureau, Fiscal Year Ended June 30, 1928
  - What the Wage-Earning Woman Contributes to Family Support, Bulletin No. 75, by Agnes Peterson, 1929
  - Conditions of Work in Spin Rooms, Bulletin No. 72, by Ethel L. Best, 1929
  - Survey of Laundries and Their Women Workers in 23 Cities, Bulletin No. 78, by Ether L. Best and Ethel Erickson, 1930
  - Immigrant Woman and Her Job, Bulletin No. 74, by Caroline Manning, 1930
  - Variations in Employment Trends of Women and Men, Bulletin No. 73, 1930
  - Industrial Home Work, Bulletin No. 79, by Emily C. Brown, 1930
  - Women in 5-and-10-Cent Stores and Limited-Price Chain Department Stores, Bulletin No. 76, by Mary Elizabeth Pidgeon, 1930
- WOMEN WORKERS, 1931-1958 DEPT. OF LABOR, WOMEN'S BUREAU (Pamphlets listed by date of publication) (Box Box 30)
  - Wages of Women in 13 States, Bulletin No. 85, by Mary Elizabeth Pidgeon, 1931
  - Fluctuation of Employment in the Radio Industry, Bulletin No. 83, by Caroline Manning, 1931
  - Industrial Experience of Women Workers at the Summer Schools, 1928 to 1930, Bulletin No. 89, by Gladys L. Palmer, Ph. D., 1931
  - Fourteenth Annual Report of the Director of the Women's Bureau, Fiscal Year Ended June 30, 1932
  - Employment of Women in Vitreous Enameling, Bulletin No. 101, by Ethel L. Best, 1932
  - Employment of Women in Slaughtering and Meat Packing, Bulletin No. 88, by Mary Elizabeth Pidgeon, 1932
  - Effects on Women of Changing Conditions in the Cigar and Cigarette Industries, Bulletin No. 100, by Caroline Manning and Harriet Byrne, 1932
  - Labor Laws for Women in the States and Territories, Bulletin No. 98, by Florence P. Smith, 1932
  - Women Workers in the Third Year of the Depression, Bulletin No. 103, 1933
  - Occupational Progress of Women, 1910 to 1930, Bulletin 104, by Mary V. Dempsea, 1933
  - Employment Fluctuations and Unemployment of Women, Bulletin No. 113, by Mary Elizabeth Pidgeon, 1933
  - Change From Manual to Dial Operation in the Telephone Industry, Bulletin No. 110, by Ethel L. Best, 1933
  - Hours, Earnings, and Employment in Cotton Mills, Bulletin No. 111, by Ethel L. Best, 1933
  - Hours and Earnings in the Leather-Glove Industry, Bulletin No. 119, by Rebecca G. Smaltz and Arcadia N. Phillips, 1934
  - Employment of Women in Offices, Bulletin No. 120, by Ethel Erickson, 1934
  - Technological Changes in Relation to Women's Employment, Bulletin No. 107, by Ethel L. Best, 1935
  - Employed Women Under N. R. A. Codes, Bulletin No. 130, by Mary Elizabeth Pidgeon, 1935
  - Variations in Wage Rates Under Corresponding Conditions, Bulletin No. 122, by Mary Elizabeth Pidgeon, 1935
  - Employment Conditions in Beauty Shops, Bulletin No. 133, by Ethel Erickson, 1935
  - Women Unemployed Seeking Relief in 1933, Bulletin No. 139, 1936
  - Effects of the Depression on Wage Earners Families, Bulletin No. 108, 1936
  - Employed Woman Homemaker in the United States: Her Responsibility for Family Support, U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau Bulletin No. 148, 1936
  - Reemployment of New England Women in Private Industry, Bulletin No. 140, by Bertha Nienberg, 1936
  - Employment in Hotels and Restaurants, Bulletin 123, by Harriet A. Byrne, 1936
  - Employment Conditions in Department Stores in 1932-33, Bulletin No. 125, by Mary Loretta Sullivan, 1936
  - Factors Affecting Wages in Power Laundries, Bulletin No. 143, by Bertha M. Nienburg and Bertha Blair, 1936
  - Piecework in the Silk-Dress Industry, Bulletin No. 141, by Ethel L. Best, 1936
  - Policy Insuring Value to the Woman Buyer and a Livelihood to Apparel Makers, Bulletin No. 146, by Bertha M. Nienburg, 1936
  - Women in Industry, Bulletin 164, by Mary Elizabeth Pidgeon, 1938
  - Trends in the Employment of Women, 1928-36, Bulletin No. 159, by Mary Elizabeth Pidgeon, 1938
  - Hours and Earnings in Certain Men's-Wear Industries: Knit Underwear, Woven Cotton Underwear, Bulletin No. 163-2, 1938
  - Hours and Earnings in Certain Men's-Wear Industries: Seamless Hosiery. Bulletin No. 163-3, 1938
  - Hours and Earnings in Certain Men's-Wear Industries: Welt Shoes, Bulletin No. 163-4, 1938
  - Hours and Earnings in Certain Men's-Wear Industries: Work Clothing, Work Shirts, Dress Shirts, Bulletin No. 163-1, 1938
  - Woman Wage Earner, Her Situation Today, Bulletin No. 172, by Elisabeth D. Benham, 1939
  - Job Histories of Women Workers at the Summer Schools 1931-34 and 1938, Bulletin No. 174, by Eleanor M. Snider, 1939
  - Employed Women and Family Support, Bulletin No. 168, 1939
  - Hours and Earnings in Certain Men's-Wear Industries: Caps and Cloth Hats, Neckwear, Work and Knit Gloves, Hankerchiefs, Bulletin No. 163-6, 1939
  - Wages and Hours in Drugs and Medicines and in Certain Toilet Preparations, Bulletin No. 171, by Arthur T. Sutherland, 1939
  - Nonworking Time of Industrial Women Workers, Bulletin No. 181, 1940
  - Earnings in the Women's and Children's Apparel Industry in the Spring of 1939, Bulletin No. 175, 1940
  - Employment Conditions in Citrus Fruit Packing, 1939, 1940
  - Hours and Earnings in Certain Men's-Wear Industries: Raincoats, Sport Jackets, Bulletin No. 163-5, 1940
  - Primer of Problems in the Millinery Industry, Bulletin No. 179, 1941
  - Earnings and Hours in Pacific Coast Fish Canneries, Bulletin No. 186, by Arthur T. Sutherland, 1941
  - Earnings of Women in Selected Manufacturing Industries, 1946, Bulletin No. 219, 1947
  - American Woman, Her Changing Role: Worker - Homemaker - Citizen, Bulletin No. 224, 1948
  - Handbook of Facts on Women Workers, Bulletin No. 225, 1948
  - Community Household Employment Programs, 1948
  - Community Problems Related to the Increased Employment of Women in Defense Areas, 1951
  - Women's Advisory Committee on Defense Manpower, 1952
  - Women as Workers: A Statistical Guide, Bulletin No. D-65, 1954
  - Women Production Workers in Major Industries, 1956
- WOMEN WORKERS, VARIOUS AUTHORS, 1959-1984 (Box Box 31)
  - Married Women Working for Pay in Eight Canadian Cities, Canadian Department of Labor, 1958
  - Women Workers in 1960: Geographical Differences, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau, Bulletin No. 284, 1962
  - "The Working Wife and Her Family's Economic Position," Monthly Labor Review, April 1962 (Reprint)
  - The World of Work Conference in Career and Job Opportunities, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau, 1962
  - Women and Work, By Marjorie E. Turner, Institute of Industrial Relations, UCLA, 1964
  - Professional Opportunities for Women, Conference Proceedings, UCB, 1964
  - Private-Household Employment, U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau, 1965
  - Report on a Consultation on the Status of Household Employment, University of Illinois, 1967
  - Report on the Task Force on Social Insurance and Taxes, Citizen's Advisory Council on the Status of Women, 1968
  - Female Labor Force in the United States: Demographic and Economic Factors Governing Its Growth and Changing Composition, By Valerie Kincade Oppenheimer, 1970
  - Changes in Differences in Earnings and Occupational Status of Men and Women, 1947-1967, By Vernon T. Clover, Texas Tech University, 1970
  - "Women at Work: Changes in the Labor Force Activity of Women," Monthly Labor Review, June 1970 (Reprint)
  - "Women's Place in the Workforce," Issues in an Industrial Society, 1971
  - We the American Women, U.S. Bureau of the Census, 1973
  - Women: A Demographic Social and Economic Presentation, By Fabian Linden, The Conference Board, 1973
  - Women and Poverty, U. S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1974
  - Families and the Rise of Working Wives: An Overview, U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, Special Labor Force Report 189, 1976
  - Women and the American Economy, U.S. Air Force Academy Special Bibliography Series No. 52, 1976
  - Employment and Economic Issues of Low Income Women: Report of a Project, U. S. Department of Labor, Women 's Bureau, 1978
  - Women Private Household Workers: A Statistical and Legislative Profile, U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau, 1978
  - Women Still in Poverty, U. S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1979
  - Socioeconomic Status of Households Headed by Women, U.S. Department of Labor, R D Monograph 72, 1979
  - Perspectives on Working Women, U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1980
  - Working Women and Public Policy, U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, Report 710, 1984
- WOMEN WORKERS--WORLD WAR II, 1940-1947 (Pamphlets listed by date of publication) (Box Box 34)
  - Effective Industrial Use of Women in the Defense Program, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau, Special Bulletin No. 1, 1940
  - First Year: Study of Women's Participation in Federal Defense Activities, U. S. Civil Service Commissioner, by Lucille Foster McMillin, 1941
  - Employment of and Demand for Women Workers in the Manufacture of Instruments--Aircraft, Optical and Fire-Control, and Surgical and Dental, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Bulletin No. 189-4, 1942
  - Report of the Conference of the Women's Bureau Advisory Committees, January 21-22, 1942, 1942
  - Your Questions as to Women in War Industries, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Bulletin No. 194, 1942
  - Employment of Women in War Production, Social Security Board, Bureau of Employment Security, 1942
  - Women in War Industries, Princeton University, Industrial Relations Section, 1942
  - Women in Industry in Wartime Britain, Speech by W. J. Leaning, 1942
  - Women in War Production, No. 22, by Thelma McKelvey, Oxford University Press, 1942
  - Womanpower to Supplement Manpower, The Manufacturers Association of Connecticut, Inc., 1942
  - War Jobs for Women, Office of War Information, 1942
  - American Women at War, National Association of Manufacturers, 1942
  - Women's Part in World War II: A List of References, Library of Congress, Division of Bibliography, 1942
  - Women in War Industry: A Selected, Annotated Bibliography, Princeton University, 1942
  - Women's Factory Employment in an Expanding Aircraft Production Program, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Bulletin No. 189-1, 1942
  - Women's Employment in Aircraft Assembly Plants in 1942, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Bulletin No. 192-1, by Ethel Erickson, 1942
  - Women's Employment in Artillery Ammunition Plants, 1942, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Bulletin No. 192-2, by Martha J. Ziegler, 1942
  - Guides for Wartime Use of Women on Farms, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Special Bulletin No. 8, 1942
  - Employment of Women in the Manufacture of Small-Arms Ammunition, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Bulletin No. 189-2, 1942
  - Employment of Women in the Manufacture of Artillery Ammunition, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Bulletin No. 189-3, 1942
  - Part-Time Employment of Women in Wartime, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Special Bulletin No. 13, 1943
  - Changes in Women's Employment During the War, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Special Bulletin No. 20, by Mary Elizabeth Pidgeon, 1944
  - Second Year: Study of Women's Participation in War Activities of the Federal Government, U. S. Civil Service Commissioner, by Lucille Foster McMillin, 1943
  - Employment of Women in the Manufacture of Cannon and Small Arms in 1942, Bulletin No. 192-3, by Margaret Kay Anderson, 1943
  - Employment of Women in the Machine-Tool Industry, 1942, Bulletin No. 192-4, by Dorothy K. Newman and Martha J. Ziegler, 1943
  - Women in Personnel and Industrial Relations Work in War Industries, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau, 1943
  - Choosing Women for War-Industry Jobs, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Special Bulletin No. 12, 1943
  - Women's Employment in the Making of Steel, 1943, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Bulletin No. 192-5, by Ethel Erickson, 1944
  - British Policies and Methods in Employing Women in Wartime, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Bulletin No. 200, by Janet M. Hooks, 1944
  - Women's Employment in Foundries, 1943, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Bulletin No. 192-7, by Frances E. P. Harnish, 1944
  - Women's Emergency Farm Service on the Pacific Coast in 1943, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Bulletin No. 204, 1945
  - Employment of Women in Army Supply Depots in 1943, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Bulletin No. 192-8, 1945
  - Women's Wartime Hours of Work: The Effect on Their Factory Performance and Home Life, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Bulletin No. 208, 1947
  - Role of Women in Wartime Britain, 1939-1945, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau, 1950
- WOMEN WORKERS--WORLD WAR II--POST-WAR RECONVERSION, 1945-1947 (Pamphlets listed by date of publication)
  - Preview as to Women Workers in Transition From War to Peace, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau Special Bulletin No. 18, 1944
  - Employment of Women in the First Post-Reconversion Year in New York State, 1946-1947, State of New York, Dept. of Labor, 1947
  - Postwar Employment Prospects for Women in the Hosiery Industry, Bulletin No. 835, U. S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1945
  - Women Workers After VJ-Day in One Community: Bridgeport, Connecticut, Bulletin No. 216, U. S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau, 1947
  - Women Workers in Ten War Production Areas and Their Postwar Employment Plans, Bulletin No. 209, U. S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau, 1946
- WOMEN WORKERS--WORLD WAR II--SAFETY, 1942-1943 U. S. DEPT. OF LABOR, WOMEN'S BUREAU (Pamphlets listed by date of publication)
  - Hazards to Women Employed in War Plants on Abrasive-Wheel Jobs, Special Bulletin No. 7, 1942
  - Safety Caps for Women in War Factories, Special Bulletin No. 9, 1942
  - Women's Effective War Work Requires Good Posture, Special Bulletin No. 10, by Margaret T. Mettert, 1943
- WOMEN WORKERS--WORLD WAR II--SOCIAL SERVICES, 1942-1944 U. S. DEPT. OF LABOR, WOMEN'S BUREAU (Pamphlets listed by date of publication)
  - Boarding Homes for Women War Workers, Special Bulletin No. 11, 1943
  - Recreation and Housing for Women War Workers, Bulletin No. 190, by Mary V. Robinson, 1942
  - Women's Effective War Work Requires Time for Meals and Rest, Special Bulletin No. 5, 1942
  - Wartime Reminders to Women Who Work: The Paying Guest, the Paid Hostess, 1943
  - The Woman Counselor in War Industries, Special Bulletin No. 16, 1944
  - Community Services for Women War Workers, Special Bulletin No. 15, 1944
  - Employment and Housing Problems of Migratory Workers in New York and New Jersey Canning Industries, 1943, Bulletin No. 198, 1944
  - Progress Report on Women War Workers' Housing, Special Bulletin No. 17, 1944
- WORLD WAR II--MIGRATION, 1941-1942 (Box Box 35, 36)
  - U. S. Congress. House. Hearings... National Defense Migration, 1941-1942. Holdings: Parts 11-34 (6 folders)
  - U. S. Congress. House. Reports...National Defense Migration, 1941-1942. Holdings: 1st Interim Report, October 21, 1941
  - 2nd Interim Report: Recommendations on Full Utilization of America's Industrial Capacity and Labor Supply in the War Effort, December 19, 1941
  - 3rd Interim Report: On the Need for a Single Procurement Agnecy to Effect All-Out War Production and Achieve Full Use of Labor Supply, March 9, 1942
  - Report: Preliminary Report and Recommendations on Problems on Evacuation of Citizens and Aliens From Military Areas, March 19, 1942
  - 4th Interim Report: Findings and Recommendations on Evacuation of Enemy Aliens and Others From Prohibited Military Zones, May 1942
  - 5th Interim Report: Recommendations on the Mobilization of Manpower for the All-Out War Effort, August 10, 1942
  - 6th Interim Report: Changes Needed for Effective Mobilization of Manpower, 1941 Final Report, 1943